CAMERON SMITH English Teacher

I'm a linguist with a passion for speech, grammar, and written language. I've been a research scientist, a writer, an engineer, and a mentor. Some of the topics that excite me are literature, linguistics, and learning new languages.

Experience

Cameron Smith Mentoring, San Francisco — Mentor

July 2021 - Present

Teach language learners at all levels the ins and outs of the English language with a focus on clear and natural communication.

Dev/Mission, San Francisco - Data Science Mentor

March 2016 - Present

I teach students the fundamentals of data science and help them begin careers in industry. Theoretical issues including linguistics, math, statistics, and deep learning are covered along with practical applications of modeling and data pipelines.

Apple, Cupertino - Natural Language Processing Engineer

March 2016 - July 2021

Worked on the Siri Text-to-Speech (TTS) team on speech synthesis, corpus creation, A/B testing, and regex rule systems. Worked in a multilingual setting with linguists on languages including 中文, and 日本語.

University of California, Merced - Graduate Student Instructor

July 2015 - March 2016

Created and evaluated lab experiments to study the evolution of language. Modeled language evolution mathematically and observed in structural data. Wrote and published scientific papers.

University of California, Berkeley - Research Associate

July 2014 - July 2015

Ran a lab whose research area was the field of color perception and categorization. Worked closely with research participants, collecting, analyzing, and visualizing data. Published <u>Language</u> evolution in the lab tends toward informative communication

Education

UC Merced - MS in Cognitive and Information Science

2015 - 2016

Doctoral program focusing on cognition and modeling. Coursework was based on experiment design, randomized controlled trials, behavioral science, and psychology.

Stanford University - Deep Learning Summer Program

2015

8-week program at the Institute for Computational and Mathematical Engineering focusing on traditional ML techniques culminating in deep learning: recurrent neural nets, CNN's, etc. and how to structure, train, and apply these models.

UC Santa Cruz - B.S. in Cognitive Science

2010 - 2014

Summa cum laude. Studied CogSci with a focus in linguistics and AI. Founded the Cognitive Science Student Association (CSSA), Students for Skeptical Inquiry, and a debate club.